Lucio Franco

Currently a Computer Science student at the University of Denver, I have a strong passion for learning, solving problems and programming. I like producing clean code, designing/architecting projects, and researching different technologies for those projects. I have experience writing APIs, Games, and Web Apps. I am very interested in distributed systems, databases and functional programming.

2225 Buchtel Blvd #202,
Denver, CO, 80210
(240)-688-6461
lucio.franco@du.edu
https://luciofran.co
https://github.com/LucioFranco

EXPERIENCE

ReadyTalk, Denver, CO — Software Engineer Intern

https://readytalk.com JUN 2016 - AUG 2016

Architected a bot that used NLP to summarize slack channels.

Ombud, Denver, CO − Software Engineer Intern

https://ombud.com

MAR 2015 - OCT 2015

Worked as the 4th member of the engineering team that built the web application for answering RFPs. Learned node/react/elasticsearch.

EDUCATION

University of Denver, Denver, CO — Honors Bachelors of Science in Computer Science

SEPT 2014 - MAY 2018 | GPA: 3.33

Courses: Algorithms & Data Structures, Parallel & Distributed Programming,
Database Organization & Management, Systems Programming, Game Networking

PROJECTS

Below are two of my more notable projects; there are many more completed or in progress on my personal site! https://luciofran.co/#projects

cobalt.rs – Static site generator

Static site generator built in Rust. I am a member of the organization and am an active contributor. github.com/cobalt-org

Amethyst — Data oriented game engine

Data oriented game engine written in Rust. I am a member of the organization and am active contributor. github.com/amethyst

SKILLS

Expert: Rust, Java, C/C++, JavaScript, Git, HTML/CSS, React.js, Docker

Intermediate: Ruby, Mysql, Postgres, Unix, Bash, CI/CD, OpenGL, Hadoop, HDFS, Public Speaking

Beginner: Go, ElasticSearch, Haskell

AWARDS

2nd place at Startup Weekend DU

3rd place at Codeday Boulder

Walter Johnson High School Computer Science Award

LANGUAGES

English(Native)

French(fluent)

Italian(Semi-fluent)